<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Blowguns (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.Blowguns</packageId>
  <author>O Negative</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/Blowguns</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies />
  <loadAfter />
  <description>Update of O Negatives mod for RimWorld 1.1
	
B18 - maintained by pgoslinga
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1812077718
Original - made by O Negative
https://ludeon.com/forums/index.php?topic=29966.0

[img]https://i.imgur.com/GYswkZ7.png[/img]

Support-chat:
https://invite.gg/mlie

Non-steam version:
https://github.com/emipa606/Blowguns
	
--- pgoslingas Description ---
Adds craftable neolithic blowguns. Prehistoric biological warfare at its finest.

C# class library and XML definitions now compatible version 18 RimWorld.

Production

You can produce blowguns at any weapon production station in the core game.
Aside from the easily obtained wood you'll need for the basic "tube" of the blowgun, you're going to need some venom for the darts.
Venom can be obtained via "milking" tamed cobras.

Antivenom can be produced at a drug lab once medicine production is researched, and you have a colonist with basic familiarity in crafting and medicine.

Original Author: O Negative
https://ludeon.com/forums/index.php?topic=29966.0

Credits:
gretino: Translation - Chinese(Simplified)
	
--- Original Description ---
With a bit of wood and some snake venom, you'll be able to produce your very own lethal or nonlethal blowdarts in no-time!
Getting wood is easy. The trick is getting the snake venom! You'll have to tame some cobras, and "milk" them for their venom.
Obviously, this is risky business, but the payoff is well worth it.

The blowgun is an incredibly short ranged weapon, that can prove useful or catastrophic for your colonists. It does minimal damage (literally), but applies one of two toxins to the target on-hit.

The lethal variation of the blowgun fires darts with concentrated snake venom on the tip.
The result is the same toxic buildup that occurs when bitten by a snake, only much more severe.
A few hits can kill even the largest beasts.

The nonlethal variation of the blowgun should only be used to hit a human target once.
Results are not immediate, but over time the tranquilizing properties of the dart will cause the target to slowly go temporarily blind and paralyzed.
The effects can last anywhere from 12 to 16 hours.

The rate and cap of each toxin's severity is determined by the body size/meat amount of your target, as well as how many darts hit your target.
You'll find this information useful if you ever find yourself wanting to tranquilize an elephant or thrumbo.

NEW - Antivenom

Antivenom is a form of modern medicine that will prove useful to your colony.
It rapidly slows, and eventually stops the progression of both forms of toxic buildup.
You will want to have a vial or two of this lying around, just in case.

Production

You can produce blowguns at any weapon production station in the core game.
Aside from the easily obtained wood you'll need for the basic "tube" of the blowgun, you're going to need some venom for the darts.
Venom can be obtained via "milking" tamed cobras.

Antivenom can be produced at a drug lab once medicine production is researched, and you have a colonist with basic familiarity in crafting and medicine.

Applications


Both of these weapons are incredibly tactical, even for the simplest AI. And, yes, tribal raiders do spawn with these from time to time.

Lethal
Quickly puts victim into a disadvantaged position, which is only exacerbated by multiple hits.
Multiple consecutive hits are guaranteed to kill, if left neglected.
HINT: Try not to get hit with a lethal dart if you don't have some antivenom lying around!

Nonlethal
Best used as a hit-and-run weapon.
Great for bringing down large/dangerous animals and other beasts.
Be careful when using it on quick predators, such as the panther.
Also useful in ending the mental breaks of colonists you don't want to risk permanently damaging.
Just remember the effects are not instant.

Toxic Fallout
Antivenom will not prevent the progression of toxic buildup entirely.
But, it can prove incredibly helpful in keeping your colonists and livestock alive until you can get the proper roofed setup ready for the duration of the event.

Colony Economy
Snake venom can be sold for a decent price, making your cobras worthy of keeping around.
Further investment of time and resources into crafting antivenom will prove even more profitable!

Feedback
The textures are rough, and I apologize for that.
Make sure to leave feedback, though! I know the mod isn't perfect, and probably never will be.
I am, however, always interested in ways to improve upon my work.</description>
</ModMetaData>